Alfred I. Hallowell Papers 1892-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
Alfred Irving Hallowell Papers
1892-1981
Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
21.0 Linear feet
Alfred Irving ("Pete") Hallowell was an anthropologist best known for his studies of Ojibwa culture and world-view, and the innovative use of the Rorschach Test in his studies of the psychological interrelations of individuals and their culture. Early in his career, Hallowell worked as a social case worker for Family Service, and even after moving on to study anthropology in 1920 (M.A.), he carried with him an interest in ethnic and racial culture, developing additional interests in psychological testing. Except for the years 1944-1947, when he taught at Northwestern University, Hallowell spent his entire career at the University of Pennsylvania where he was professor of anthropology, professor of anthropological psychiatry in the Medical School, and curator of social anthropology at the University Museum. A cultural anthropologist, Hallowell's use of clinical psychological methods, especially Rorschach tests, was both innovative and controversial in his discipline. In his research, he concentrated on the Algonkian Indians, especially the Abenaki and Ojibwa Indians of Canada and Wisconsin (Berens River, Lake Winnipeg, Manitoba, and Lac du Flambeau, Wisconsin areas), and the Saulteaux of Berens River. The Alfred Irving Hallowell Papers (1892-1981) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Hallowell, papers by colleagues and students, research notes kept by Hallowell, with a special emphasis on social organization, personality, behavior, psychology, religion, and folklore. The collection of several hundred photographs provides rich graphic documentation of Hallowell's work among the Ojibwa and Abnaki Indians during the 1930s.
Hallowell, A. Irving, (Alfred Irving), 1892-1974
General note
While there is no container listing for all sub-series in Series VI, many of the photographs have been reproduced for research use, and arranged and described. The photographs and negatives that pertain to Hallowell's research on Native Americans in the United States and Canada were chosen for reproduction (Subseries A-F). Postcards were not reproduced. Each unique image in Subseries A-F has a research photograph and a copy negative. The research photographs have been reprinted from the original negative when possible.
A description of each reproduced item is included in the appendix as well as a detailed narrative of the photograph conservation project.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Hallowell Papers were donated to the APS Library by Geraldine M. Frame in 1983 (Accession #1983-1605ms).
General note
During processing, the collection was re-foldered and re-housed in acid-free folders and boxes. Metal fasteners were removed and replaced with plastic clips when necessary. A separate listing of torn or severely deteriorated manuscripts and manuscripts that need to have glue and tape removed has been compiled by series and submitted to the Conservation Department.
All newspaper clippings were photocopied onto acid-free paper; the original clippings were then discarded. Other brittle or torn items were also photocopied, and when considered valuable, were retained.
For information on the conservation of the photographs and negatives, all of which are in Series VI, please see the appendix.
Scope and Contents note
The Alfred Irving Hallowell Papers (1892-1981) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Hallowell, papers by colleagues and students, research notes kept by Hallowell, and photographs, which document Hallowell's career as an anthropologist.
The papers (47 boxes; 8 albums; 30 linear feet) are divided into five series:
Series I. Correspondence 1919-1981 (11 boxes; 5.75 linear feet)
Series II. Subject Files 1921-1976 (2 boxes;.75 linear feet)
Series III. Works by Hallowell 1917-1974 (6 boxes; 3 linear feet)
Series IV. Works by Others 1923-1976 (3 boxes; 1.5 linear feet)
Series V. Research Notes 1892-1964 (18 boxes; 9 linear feet)
Series VI. Photographs 1890s-1971 (8 albums and 4 boxes)
Oversized materials either follow the same series arrangement as noted above or are arranged as noted in an appended folder listing. Cross referencing to oversized material appears on the folders in the standard sized boxes. Reprints have been moved to the printed materials collection of the APS library. If a reprint was found as an enclosure, a photocopy of the title page was filed in its place. To retrieve reprints, consult the card catalog for printed materials.
Biographical/Historical note
Alfred Irving ("Pete") Hallowell was an anthropologist best known for his studies of Ojibwa culture and their world-view, and the innovative use of the Rorschach Test in his studies of the psychological interrelations of individuals and their culture. He was born on 28 December 1892 in Philadelphia, the son of Edgar Lloyd and Dorothy Edsall Hallowell. After a three-year course at a manual high school, Hallowell attended the Wharton School of Finance and Commerce of the University of Pennsylvania. Since at that time the Wharton School was home to the social sciences and had a flexible curriculum, Hallowell took several elective courses in sociology and economics. By the time he graduated in 1914, Hallowell had abandoned the idea of a business career in favor of one in the social sciences. Hallowell lacked the finances to continue with graduate studies immediately, so he became a caseworker with the Family Society and took courses in anthropology on the side. Lectures by Alexander A. Goldenweiser, an anthropologist at the Pennsylvania School of Social Work, introduced Hallowell to the use of psychoanalytic theory in social science. He also took several courses with anthropologist Frank G. Speck at the University of Pennsylvania, who inspired Hallowell's interest in working with Native American cultures.
Speck helped Hallowell obtain a Harrison Fellowship so that he could pursue full-time graduate work in anthropology at the University of Pennsylvania. Hallowell earned an master's degree in 1920, and his thesis research involved fish nets and netting in North America. In 1924 Hallowell received a PhD in anthropology. His dissertation, "Bear Ceremonialism in the Northern Hemisphere," was published as an entire issue of American Anthropologist in 1926. This study reveals the complex system of beliefs and ceremonies about the bear that were practiced among primitive peoples living throughout the circumboreal culture area of northern Europe, Asia, and North America.
Hallowell's field studies, which began in the late 1920s, involved the Abenaki of Quebec; the Montagnais-Naskapi of Labrador; and especially the Ojibwa-speaking peoples of the Lake Winnipeg region. His studies provide a complete ethnographic record of Ojibwa culture, including aspects of kinship and social organization, economics, technology, ecological relationships, medicine, religion, and folklore. Hallowell went beyond ethnological issues to those involving the psychological dimensions of Ojibwa acculturation. Such pioneering research required the development of new methodology, and Hallowell chose to make use of the then-new Rorschach Tests. Hallowell saw the Rorschach Test as a subtle and relatively culture-free way of probing the complexities of personality. Additionally, the Rorschach Test allowed comparisons on both an individual and group basis. Hallowell published several works on both the methodological theory and field use of Rorschach Tests, including "Rorschach Protocols of 151 Berens River Adults and Children and 155 Adults From Lac du Flambeau," and "The Rorschach Technique in Personality and Culture Studies."
In later years Hallowell's research involved the history of Native American-white relationships and the history of anthropology. Before Hallowell, little had been written on the impact of Native Americans on Euro-American culture. His ground-breaking studies in this area culminated in such publications as "The Backwash of the Frontier: The Impact of the Indian on American Culture." Hallowell's later studies also included the psychological dimension of human evolution, which brought together "as an integral whole the organic, psychological, social, and cultural dimensions of the evolutionary process as they relate to the underlying conditions necessary for human existence." (See Series III, "On Being an Anthropologist: Some Autobiographical Reflections," p. 13.) His publications in this area include "Personality Structure and the Evolution of Man," and "Hominid Evolution, Cultural Adaptation, and Mental Dysfunction.
Except for three years (1944-1947) at Northwestern University, Hallowell spent his entire professional career at the University of Pennsylvania. Hallowell began there in 1922 as an instructor in anthropology, progressing to the the rank of professor in 1939 and chairman of the department in 1941. Between 1947 and 1971, Hallowell was professor of anthropology in psychiatry and curator of social anthropology at the University Museum. After his retirement, he remained active as a visiting professor at the University of Washington, the University of Wisconsin, Bryn Mawr College, the University of Chicago, Temple University, and Chatham College. Throughout his career, Hallowell was an active member of professional societies, serving as president of the American Anthropological Association and the American Folklore Society, chairman of the Division of Anthropology and Psychology of the National Research Council; and a board member of the American Council of Learned Societies and the International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences. He was editor of the American Ethnological Society Monograph series, as well as of publications of the Wenner-Gren Foundation.
Hallowell's professional service and achievements have earned the deep respect of his colleagues and students. Two publications have been printed in his honor: 1) Culture and Experience, in honor of his sixtieth birthday; and 2) Context and Meaning in Cultural Anthropology, his festschrift edited by Melford E. Spiro. In 1976 Fogelson et al. published Contributions to Anthropology: Selected Papers of A. Irving Hallowell, a collection of Hallowell's later works that serves as a complementary volume to Culture and Experience. Hallowell's numerous awards include a Guggenheim fellowship (1940-1941) for studies of personality in primitive cultures; the Viking Medal (1956) for outstanding achievement in anthropology; and memberships in the National Academy of Sciences (1961) and the American Philosophical Society (1963).
Hallowell died, after a long illness, in Wayne, Pennsylvania, on 10 October 1974. He was survived by his wife, Maude Frame Hallowell.
Azikiwe, Nnamdi, 1904-1996; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942; Bunzel, Ruth Leah, 1898-; Casagrande, Joseph B., (Joseph Bartholomew), 1915-1982; Day, Gordon M.; Eggan, Fred, 1906-1991; Eiseley, Loren C., 1907-1977; Erminie Wheeler-Voegelin, 1903-1988; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Hilger, M. Inez, (Mary Inez), 1891-1977; Hoebel, E. Adamson (Edward Adamson), 1906-1993; Klopfer, Bruno; Kluckhorn, Clyden Kay; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960; Leighton, Dorothea Cross, 1908-; Linton, Ralph, 1893-1953; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Moe, Henry Allen, 1894-1975; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941; Roe, Anne, 1904-; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950; Spier, Leslie, 1893-1961; Spiro, Melford E.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-; Abenaki Indians; Abenaki language; Acculturation.; Algonquian Indians--Canada; Algonquian Indians--Religion and mythology; Algonquian Indians--Social life and customs; Algonquian Indians--United States; Autobiographies.; Aztecs.; Bears--Folklore; Bears--Mythology; Bibliographies.; Biographies.; Card catalogs.; Cherokee children; Dictionaries.; Dissertations.; Drawings.; Essays.; Field notes.; Fishing nets; Gelatin silver prints; Genealogies; Histories; Hopi Indians; Illustrations; Indians of Mexico; Indians of North America--Arizona; Indians of North America--Canada; Indians of North America--Manitoba; Indians of North America--New Mexico; Indians of North America--Ontario; Indians of North America--Quebec (Province); Interviews; Language and culture; Lecture notes; Lectures; Manitoba--Maps; Manuscripts; Maps; Material culture; Memorabilia; Mohegan Indians--Social life and customs; Navajo Indians; Nitrate negatives; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa children--United States; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Religion and mythology; Ojibwa Indians--United States; Ojibwa language; Ontario--Maps; Personality and culture; Personality tests; Photographs; Projective techniques; Psychoanalysis; Psychoanalysis and culture; Religion and culture; Rorschach test; Sketches.; Social evolution.; Sub-Arctic Indians; Thematic Apperception Test.
- Series I. Correspondence, 1919-1973 (Box 1-11)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains the incoming and outgoing manuscript and typescript letters, carbons, telegrams, and postcards generated by Hallowell and his colleagues, Native American field informants, students, and family. Professional correspondence includes a letter from Elsie Clews Parsons regarding the American Folklore Society and a letter from Franz Boas in reference to Kwakiutl bear ceremonialism. Native American correspondents include Chief William Berens and Henry L. Masta. Of interest is Hallowell's correspondence with his former student Nnamdi Azikiwe, who invited Hallowell to speak at his installation as Governor-General and Commander-in-Chief of Nigeria in 1961 (see also Series II, Nigeria; and Series III, "To Nigeria"). The series also includes personal correspondence with Dorothy Kern Hallowell, Hallowell's first wife and the mother of William H. Hallowell, during the time when their son was incarcerated at the Eastern State Penitentiary in Philadelphia.
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name and then chronologically within each folder. When a correspondence file includes letters to a third party (i.e., not Hallowell), the name is indicated on the container list by using an indent under the folder title.
  Unidentified correspondence has been filed as "Unidentified" and is arranged chronologically. Enclosed manuscripts have been removed from this series and placed in Series III or IV as appropriate. As with the reprints, a photocopy of the title page was filed with the original letter. Letters of reference are filed under the name of the person who is the subject of the letter.
  - Aberle, David F., 1954 (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.II, "Special Session: The Problem of Group Character"-- Introduction
  - Abramson, Edward J., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Abt, Lawrence Edwin, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Academy of Psychoanalysis, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, K.J., 1961 (Box 1)
  - Ackerknecht, Erwin H., 1944-1947 (Box 1)
  - Adams, June Macklin (Box 1)
    -See Ser.I, Macklin, Barbara June
  - Admas, Ruth, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Adelman, Fred, 1956-1967 (Box 1)
  - Adrian, Audrey, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Aginsky, Burt W., 1942 (Box 1)
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Martin G., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Allport, Gordon W., 1938, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Alter, J. Cecil, 1954 (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1945 (Box 1)
  - American Anthropological Association, 1946-1971 (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.I, Beals, Ralph
    -See also Ser.I, Redfield, Robert
    -See also Ser.II, same title
  - American Anthropological Association. Reorganization Committee, 1945-1946; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Anthropological Association. Symposium on Human Nature, 1952, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.I, Bidney, David
    -See also Ser.I, Gillin, John Philip
    -See also Ser.I, Washburn, Sherwood Larned
  - American Anthropologist, 1935-1965 (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1954-1958 (Box 1)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1942-1945 (Box 1)
  - American Ethnological Society, [1950], 1960 (Box 1)
  - American Folklore Society, 1968-1969, n.d. (Box 1)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Inc., 1961 (Box 1)
  - American Historical Association, 1954 (Box 1)
  - American Indian Ethnohistoric Conference (Box 1)
    -See Ser.I, American Society for Ethnohistory
  - American Journal of Orthopsychiatry, 1950 (Box 1)
  - American Journal of Psychiatry, 1949 (Box 1)
  - American Men of Science, n.d. (Box 1)
  - American Museum of Natural History (N.Y.). Department of Anthropology, 1946 (Box 1)
  - American Orthopsychiatric Association, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.I, Jules, Henry
  - American Philosophical Society, 1946-1970 (Box 1)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association, 1969 (Box 1)
  - American Psychological Association, 1946, 1958-1962 (Box 1)
  - American Psychopathological Association, Inc., 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - American Public Health Association, 1950 (Box 1)
  - American Society for Ethnohistory, 1965 (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.I, American Indian Ethnohistoric Conference
  - American Sociological Review, 1956-1963 (Box 1)
  - American Wildlife Institute, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Anastasi, Anne, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Andrew, Gwen (Box 1)
    -See Ser.I, Michigan. Department of Mental Health
  - The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1945-1946, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Annual Review of Anthropology, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Ansari, A.K. Junaid, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Anthony, H.E., 1934 (Box 1)
  - Anthropological Society of Washington, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
  - Appel, Kenneth E., 1953-1962 (Box 1)
  - D. Appleton- Century Co., Inc., 1945 (Box 1)
  - Arbuckle, John, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Ardrey, Robert, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Arseneau, Calixte, 1926 (Box 1)
    in French
  - Asch, Solomon E., 1957 (Box 1)
  - Ashley-Montagu, Montague Francis, 1942-1960 (Box 1)
  - Asia Foundation, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Atheneum Publishers, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Athey, Elizabeth, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Atkins, John, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.II, Nigeria
    -See also Ser.III, "To Nigeria"
  - Baden, Sani E., 1948 (Box 1)
  - Baerreis, David A., 1955 (Box 1)
  - Baldessane, Thelma, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Marvela V., 1946 (Box 1)
  - Balikei, Asen, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Baller, Warren R., 1959 (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.I, Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc.
  - Bank Street College of Education, New York, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Barbeau, C. Marius, 1945, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Barbeck, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Bard College, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Barens, Harry E., 1926 (Box 1)
  - Barnett, H.G., 1946-1956 (Box 1)
  - Barnett, James H., 1949-1954 (Box 1)
  - Barnouw, Victor, 1944-1971 (Box 1)
  - Bascom, William R., 1946-1971 (Box 1)
  - Beaglehole, Ernest, 1937, 1950-1961 (Box 1)
  - Beals, Ralph L., 1949-1956 (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.I, American Anthropological Association
  - Beck, Horace P., Jr., [1958], n.d. (Box 1)
    -See also Ser.I, Fenton, William Nelson
  - Beck, Samuel J., 1938-1970 (Box 1)
  - Becker, Ernest, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Becker, Howard, 1941-1946, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Becker, Marshall Joseph, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Behavior Science Notes, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Bellinger, John W., 1961 (Box 1)
  - Beltrán, Gonzalo Aguirre, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Anna, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Ruth, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, John W., 1947 (Box 1)
  - Benson, C. Randolph, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Bentley, Harold W., 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bere, May, 1945 (Box 2)
    -See also Ser.I, Berens, William
  - Berens, William, 1935-1947 (Box 2)
    -See also Ser.I, Bere, May
  - Beres, David, 1958-1961 (Box 2)
  - Bergen, Bernard J., 1965 (Box 2)
  - Berndt, Fredrick, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Bessler, Hans, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Bidney, David, 1946-1953 (Box 2)
    -See also Ser.I, American Anthropological Association. Symposium on Human Nature, 1952
  - Bieder, Robert E., 1972 (Box 2)
  - Bierer, Joshua (Box 2)
    -See Ser.I, International Congress of Social Psychiatry
  - Biesheuvel, S., 1951 (Box 2)
  - Birket-Smith, Kaj, 1926-1937 (Box 2)
  - Bishop, William Warner, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Black, Mary B., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Bloom, Lynn Z., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Blumenfeld, Ruth, 1956-1962 (Box 2)
  - Boas, Franz, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Bock, Kenneth E., 1953-1962 (Box 2)
  - Bodde, Derk, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Boewe, Charles, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Boggs, Stephen Taylor, 1952-1963 (Box 2)
  - Boglár, L., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Bohannen, Paul, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Boles, John, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Borhegyi, Stephan F., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Boshes, Louis D., 1946 (Box 2)
  - Bourguignon, Erika Eichhorn, 1945-1963 (Box 2)
    Peterson, Alberta
    -See also Ser.I, Northwestern University
  - Bourliére, F., 1946 (Box 2)
  - Bouthillier, Eva N., 1941 (Box 2)
  - Bowles, Gordon T., 1946 (Box 2)
  - Boyer, L. Bryce, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Bradley, Sculley, 1951-1955 (Box 2)
  - Brameld, Theodore, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
  - Brand, Donald D., 1942, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Brand, Howard, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Brandeis University, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Brenman, Margaret, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Briggs, Katherine M., 1942 (Box 2)
  - Broberg, William E., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Brown, G. Gordon, 1944, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Joseph E., 1959 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Mary K. (Mrs. Nicholas C.), 1967 (Box 2)
  - Bruner, Edward M., 1958 (Box 2)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Buchler, Ira R., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Buerkle, Jack V., 1965 (Box 2)
  - Bunn, Edward B. (Box 2)
    -See Ser.I, Georgetown University
  - Bunzel, Ruth Leah, 1938, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Burgess, Ernest W., 1948 (Box 2)
  - Burgess, J. Stewart, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Burkholder, David, 1956-1958 (Box 2)
  - Busia, Kofi A., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Butler, Ruth Lapham, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Cabot, William B. (Box 2)
    -See Ser.I, Speck, Frank Gouldsmith
  - Calabresi, Viola, 1956 (Box 2)
  - California State College at Long Beach, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Callaway, Katherine, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, T. Moody, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Canada. Department of Indian Affairs, 1932-1963 (Box 2)
  - Canada. Department of Justice, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Cantril, Hadley, 1947-1951 (Box 2)
  - Carci, Marthe, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Eric T., 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Gustav G., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Carpenter, C.R., 1956-1960 (Box 2)
  - Carpenter, Edmund Snow, 1952-1957 (Box 2)
  - Carstairs, Morris, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Cartwright, B.W., 1936 (Box 2)
  - Cary, John R., 1961 (Box 2)
  - Casagrande, Joseph B., 1949-1962 (Box 2)
  - Caudill, William, 1949-1960, n.d. (Box 2)
    Redlich, F.C.
  - Chance, Michael R.A., 1959 (Box 2)
  - Chance, Norman Allee, 1955-1967 (Box 2)
  - Chandler Publishing Co., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Chaput, Donald, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Chase, Fannie S., 1932 (Box 2)
  - Chernetsov, V., 1964 (Box 2)
  - CIBA Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Clark, W.R. (Box 2)
    -See also Ser.I, Speck, Frank Gouldsmith
  - Clarke, Eunic A., 1970 (Box 2)
  - Claudel, Alice Moser (Mrs. Calvin), 1953 (Box 2)
  - Clifton, James A., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Codère, Helen, 1951-1962 (Box 2)
  - Coelho, Ruy GalvC#o de Andrada, 1946-1956 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Felix S. and Lucy, 1952-1959 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Ronald, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Yehudi A., 1955-1967 (Box 2)
  - Cole, John T., 1958-1968 (Box 2)
  - Collins, Henry B., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Collio, J.M., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Columbia University. Graduate Anthropology Club, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Columbia University Press, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Committee for the Study of Animal Societies Under Natural Conditions, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Companhia Editoria Nacional, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Comparative Studies in Society and History, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Conference on Public Health and the Behavioral Sciences, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Congregational and Christian Churches. Race Relations Division (Box 2)